你有事吗
What do you want?
护士让我来的 先生
The nurse sent me, sir.
我在上英语课 然后有点头痛
I was in English and I got a headache.
别烦我 回家去
Then don't bother me, go home.
我不能
I can't.
为什么 你妈妈工作去了
Why? Is your mother at work?
我住在安布罗斯山孤儿院
I live in Ambrose Hall, the children's home.
没有父母
No parents?
没有人想念你
No one to miss you?
我明白护士为什么送你来了
I see why the nurse sent you.
可怜的孩子
You poor child.
可怜的…
Poor,
瘦弱的孩子
thin child.
进来吧
Come inside.
午饭时间快到了
It's nearly time for lunch.
早上好 同学们
Good morning, class.
大家都坐好了吗
Are we sitting comfortably?
那么…
So...
物理
physics.
物理 是吧
Physics, eh?
物理
Physics.
物理 物理 物理 物理 物理 物理
Physics. Physics. Physics. Physics. Physics. Physics.
物理
Physics!
大家请记一下笔记
I hope one of you is getting all this down.
好的 看看你们懂多少
Okay, let's see what you know.
把两根相同的尼龙绳
Two identical strips of nylon
把它们都充满静电
are charged with static electricity
竖直悬挂于细绳上使它们能自由摆动
and hung from a string so they can swing freely.
使两根尼龙绳靠近时会发生什么
What would happen if they were brought near each other?
好的 你叫什么名字
Yes, what's your name?
米洛
Milo.
米洛 你说吧
Milo. Off you go.
他们会互相排斥 因为他们有相同电荷
They'd repel each other because they have the same charge.
完全正确
Correct-amundo.
这个词我之前从没说过
A word I have never used before
希望以后再不会使用
and hopefully never will again.
问题二 我卷起一条镍铬合金导线
Question two. I coil up a thin piece of nichrome wire
然后放进一杯水里
and place it in a glass of water.
然后通上电
Then I turn on the electricity
并测量水温有没受到影响
and measure to see if the water temperature is affected.
我的问题是
My question is this.
怎样才能测量流过导线的电能
How do I measure the electrical power going into the coil?
还有其他人吗
Someone else.
没有 好的 米洛你来
No? Okay. Milo, go for it.
用电流表测电流 电压表测电压
Measure the current and PD using an ammeter and voltmeter.
两题全对 对了米洛 告诉我
Two to Milo! Right, Milo, tell me this.
判断题 某系统的减震器越大
True or false, the greater the damping on a system,
系统向环境损失能量越快
the quicker it loses energy to its surroundings.
错
False.
什么是非编码DNA
What is non-coding DNA?
不产生蛋白质的DNA
DNA that doesn't code for a protein.
65983乘以5等于
65,983 times 5.
怎样使运动超越光速
How do you travel faster than light?
控制36.7循环填充系数的量子隧道
By harnessing a quantum tunnel with an FILL factor of 36.7 recurring.
两天了
Two days.
抱歉 你能不能…
Sorry, could you just...
那里有些肉汁
There's a bit of gravy.
不不 只有那儿
No, no, just there.
我们来这里两天了
Two days we've been here.
怪你的男朋友吧 是他让我们到这里来的
Blame your boyfriend. He's the one who put us on to this.
他是对的 今早我的班里
He was right. Boy in class this morning,
有个男孩懂得远超地球水平的知识
got knowledge way beyond planet Earth.
你在吃那些薯条
You eating those chips?
是的 它们有点…特别
Yeah, they're a bit... different.
我觉得很好吃
I think they're gorgeous.
我上学时晚餐也能这样就好了
Wish I had school dinners like this.
这地方纪律非常好
It's very well behaved this place.
我还以为他们会像"打耳光小分队"那样乱呢
I thought they'd all be happy-slapping hoodies.
打耳光小分队和《反社会行为法令》
Happy-slapping hoodies with ASBOs.
打耳光小分队和《反社会行为法令》 和铃声
Happy-slapping hoodies with ASBOs and ringtones. Eh?
怎么样 还说我不能融入这里
Don't tell me I don't fit in.
上班时间不允许离开岗位
You are not permitted to leave your station during a sitting.
我只是和这位老师说说话
I was just talking to this teacher.
你好
Hello.
他不喜欢这些薯条
He doesn't like the chips.
菜单是校长特别定制的
The menu has been specifically designed by the headmaster
用来改善学生注意力和纪律
to improve concentration and performance.
现在回去干活
Now get back to work.
看到了吗 这就是我
See? This is me.
一个食堂大妈
Dinner lady.
我快崩溃了
I'll have the crumble.
我好想杀了你
I'm so gonna kill you.
梅丽莎
Melissa.
下个学期你来我的班
You'll be joining my class for the next period.
米洛让我失望了 现在是时候把你调到尖子班了
Milo's failed me so it's time we moved you up to the top class.
肯尼 不吃薯条啊
Kenny, not eating the chips?
爸妈不允许
I'm not allowed.
卢克 马上来补习班
Luke, extra class. Now!
小心点 稳住 一滴也不要溅出来
WOMAN: Careful, keep it steady. Don't spill a drop.
我说 稳住 小心点
I said keep it steady. Careful.
就是这样 小心点 稳住
That's it. Easy now. Steady.
好 第二桶了 现在迅速点
Right, second barrel, quickly now.
有什么消息了
What have you got?
确认
Confirmation.
我刚进入了军方的记录
I just got into army records.
三个月前 有大型UFO活动行为
Three months ago, massive UFO activity.
他们记录了超过40次目击
They logged over 40 sightings.
天空中奇怪的光 就这些
Lights in the sky, all of that.
我搞不到图片 因为全都是机密
Can't get any photos 'cause then it gets all classified, secret.
总是把我挡在外面
Keeps locking me out.
跟你说吧
Tell you what; though.
三个月前 厨房的员工全都被换掉了
Three months ago, turns out all the kitchen staff were replaced.
这些人相当古怪
And this lot are weird.
看吧 这里面绝对有阴谋
There's definitely something going on.
我叫你回来是对的
I was right to call you home.
我以为也许你叫我回家只是
I thought maybe you called me home just...
只是为了叫我回家
Well, just to call me home.
你以为我编了个紧急事件
Do you think I'd just invent an emergency?
不是没可能
You could've done.
那是我最不可能做的事
That's the last thing I'd do.
因为我每次见你 总是被紧急事件阻碍
'Cause every time I see you, an emergency just gets in the way.
我得挂了
I've got to go.
拉她起来 拉起来
Get her up, get her up!
洛斯 那是什么 怎么…
Rose, what is it? What...
你在干嘛
What you doing?
叫急救车啊
Calling an ambulance.
不需要 她没什么事
No need, she's quite all right.
没事 她经常这样
It's fine. She does that.
请大家马上把耳机都带上
I'd like you all to put your headphones on now, please.
噢 孩子们
Oh, children,
你们将要大开眼界
the things you will see.
数学 那是我们工作的基础
Mathematics. That's the cornerstone of our work here.
但我的改进并不仅限于在班级 不不不
But my improvements aren't confined to the classroom. No, no, no.
我们引入了一套新的政策
We've introduced a new policy here.
学校正餐完全免费
School dinners are absolutely free,
但是是强制性的
but compulsory.
请一定尝尝薯条
Do try the chips.
噢 很乐意 谢谢
Oh, I'd love to, thank you.
不得不说
And it's got to be said,
你的改革带来的的成效 真的很惊人
the transformation you've brought about, it's amazing.
也许你对孩子们有点太苛刻了 会不会
I mean, maybe you're working the children a little bit too hard now and then,
但我认为好结果比什么都重要
but I think good results are more important than anything.
正确 你是个有眼光的女人 史密斯女士
Exactly. You're a woman of vision, Miss Smith.
我能看到一切 芬奇先生 非常清楚
Oh, I can see everything, Mr Finch. Quite clearly.
昨天有个12岁的女生
Yesterday I had a 12-year-old girl
说出了特洛伊墙的准确高度
give me the exact height of the walls of Troy
以肘为单位
in cubits.
那是新校长来了之后的事吗
And it's ever since the new headmaster arrived?
芬奇三个月前上任
Finch arrived three months ago,
第二天一半职员得了流感
next day half the staff got flu.
芬奇就用那些人替代了原来的
Finch replaced them with that lot.
除了你替代的那个老师
Except for the teacher you replaced,
那个简直太诡异了
and that was just plain weird,
她就这么中了彩票
her winning the lottery like that.
怎么奇怪
How's that weird?
她根本不买彩票
She never played.
她说彩票是半夜从门缝底下投进来的
Said the ticket was posted through her door at midnight.
嗯
Hmm?
大千世界无奇不有
The world is very strange.
打扰了 同事们
FINCH: Excuse me, colleagues.
占用一下你们的时间
A moment of your time.
请让我介绍莎拉·简·史密斯小姐
May I introduce Miss Sarah Jane Smith.
史密斯小姐是名记者
Miss Smith is a journalist
她要为《周日时报》 写一篇我的小传
who's writing a profile about me for The Sunday Times.
我觉得她最好是能
I thought it might be useful for her to get
亲自体会一下比较方便
a view from the trenches, so to speak.
别给学校丢脸哦
Don't spare my blushes.
你好
Hello.
噢 我觉得是的
Oh, I should think so.
你是...
And you are?
恩…呃
Mmm? Uh,
史密斯 约翰·史密斯
Mmm? Uh, Smith.John Smith.
约翰·史密斯
John Smith?
我曾有个朋友时常会用这个名字
I used to have a friend who sometimes went by that name.
是啊 是个很普通的名字
Well, it's a very common name.
他是个非同寻常的人
He WAS a very uncommon man.
见到你很高兴
Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you!
是的 非常高兴
Yes. Very nice.
何止是高兴 简直棒极了
More than nice. Brilliant.
恩 那么
So,
你在这里工作很久了
have you worked here long?
不是 我才到这里两天
No, it's only my second day.
噢 你是新老师
Oh, you're new, then?
那你觉得这学校如何
So what do you think of the school?
我是说 新的课程
I mean, this new curriculum,
好多学生生病了
so many children getting ill.
你不觉得很古怪吗
Doesn't that strike you as odd?
你不像是仅仅来采访校长那么简单
You don't sound like someone just doing a profile.
既然来了 做点调查也没什么坏处
Well, no harm in a little investigation while I'm here.
没错 你真不错 你好样的
No, good for you. Good for you.
你好样的 莎拉·简·史密斯
Oh, good for you, Sarah Jane Smith.
这儿不是你的教室 肯尼 快走开
This isn't your classroom, Kenny. Now run along.
噢 晚上来看学校好奇怪
ROSE: Oh! It's weird seeing school at night.
感觉很不对
It just feels wrong.
我小的时候
When I was a kid,
还以为所有老师都是睡在学校的
I used to think all the teachers slept in school.
好了 小队
All right, team...
噢 我讨厌说"小队"
I hate people who say "team".
同伙们
Uh, gang
同志们
comrades.
不管了 洛斯 到厨房取点那种油的样本
Anyway, Rose, go to the kitchen, get a sample of that oil.
米奇 新来的老师都是数学老师
Mickey, the new staff are all maths teachers.
你去数学部门看看
Check out the maths department.
我到芬奇的办公室看看
I'm gonna look in Finch's office.
十分钟后回来这里碰头
Meet back here in 10 minutes.
你会没事吧
You gonna be all right?
我 拜托
Me? Please.
渗透和调查
Infiltration and investigation?
我可是这方面的专家
I'm an expert at this.
数学部门在哪
Where's the maths department?
一直走 左转 穿过防火门右转
Down there, turn left, through the fire doors, on the right.
谢谢
Thank you.
你好 莎拉·简
Hello, Sarah Jane.
是你
It's you.
博士
Doctor.
噢 天哪 是你
Oh, my God. It's you, isn't it?
你又重生了
You've regenerated.
是的
Yeah.
自从上次见面 我都重生过六次了
Half a dozen times since we last met.
你看起来…
You look...
非常不错
incredible.
你也是
So do you.
我变老了
I got old.
你来这里干嘛
What are you doing here?
这个嘛 UFO目击事件
Well, UFO sighting,
一间学校迹向可疑 我忍不住
school gets record results. I couldn't resist.
你呢
What about you?
一样
The same.
我以为你死了
I thought you'd died.
我一直等你 而你没有回来 我以为你一定是死了
I waited for you, you didn't come back and I thought you must have died.
我活着 其他人死了
I lived. Everyone else died.
什么意思
What do you mean?
所有人都死了 莎拉
Everyone died, Sarah.
真不敢相信是你
I can't believe it's you.
好吧 现在我能了
Okay, now I can.
你听到没
Did you hear that?
她是谁
Who's she?
洛斯 这是莎拉·简 莎拉·简 这是洛斯
Rose, Sarah Jane. Sarah Jane, Rose.
你好 很高兴见到你
Hi. Nice to meet you.
可以看出随着你的年龄增长
You can tell you're getting older,
你的助手却越来越年轻了
your assistants are getting younger.
我不是他的助手
I'm not his assistant.
不是
No?
抓到你了 小老虎
Get you, tiger.
抱歉 只是我
Sorry. Sorry, it was only me.
你让我去调查 所以
You told me to investigate, so
我开始去查看这些橱柜
I started looking through these cupboards
然后这些都掉到我身上
and all these fell out on me.
噢 天啊 全是老鼠
Oh, my God, they're rats.
一大堆老鼠
Dozens of rats.
真空包装的老鼠
Vacuum-packed rats!
然后你决定尖叫
And you decided to scream?
吓了我一跳啊
It took me by surprise.
像个小女孩一样
Like a little girl.
好黑呀 还满身是老鼠
It was dark! I was covered in rats!
九岁或者十岁 留着辫子 穿着花裙子那种
Nine, maybe ten years old. I'm seeing pigtails, frilly skirt.
各位 能不能集中注意
ROSE: Hello, can we focus?
有人发现这有什么奇怪的吗
Has anyone noticed anything strange about this?
学校里的耗子
Rats in school?
很明显 是生物课上用的
Well, obviously, they use them in biology lessons,
做解剖实验
they dissect them.
也许你还没学到那里
Or maybe you haven't reached that bit yet.
你多少岁了
How old are you?
抱歉 现在学校已经不再解剖老鼠了
Excuse me, no one dissects rats in school anymore.
他们很多年不这么做了
They haven't done that for years.
你是从黑暗时代来的吗
Where are you from, the Dark Ages?
总之 继续行动
Anyway! Moving on...
一切都是在芬奇先生来了以后出现的
Everything started when Mr Finch arrived.
我们应该去查查他的办公室
We should go and check his office.
我不是有意这么无礼
I don't mean to be rude or anything,
但你到底是什么人
but who exactly are you?
莎拉·简·史密斯
Sarah Jane Smith.
我以前和博士一起旅行
I used to travel with the Doctor.
噢 他从没提到过你
Oh! Well, he's never mentioned you.
我肯定提过
Oh, I must've done.
莎拉·简 我经常提起她
Sarah Jane. I mention her all the time.
等等
Hold on,
我想想
sorry...
从来没有
never.
什么 一次也没有
What, not even once?
他一次都没提起过我
He didn't mention me even once?
噢 老兄 现任和前任
Oh, mate. The missus and the ex.
欢迎来到男人的噩梦
Welcome to every man's worst nightmare.
也许那些老鼠是食物
DOCTOR: Maybe those rats were food.
什么的食物
Food for what?
洛斯
Rose.
你说你曾以为所有老师都睡在学校
You know how you used to think all the teachers slept in the school?
他们确实是
Well, they do.
不是吧
MICKEY: No way!
我绝不会再回到那里 不行
I am not going back in there. No way!
那些就是老师
Those were the teachers?
自从芬奇来了 他带来七个老师
When Finch arrived, he brought with him seven new teachers,
四个食堂大妈 一个护士 总共十三个
four dinner ladies and a nurse, 13.
十三个大蝙蝠人 来吧
Thirteen big bat people. Come on.
你一定是在逗我
You've got to be kidding.
我需要塔迪斯 必须分析厨房里的那些油
I need the Tardis. I've got to analyse that oil from the kitchen.
我也许能帮到你 我有东西要给你看
I might be able to help you there. I've got something to show you.
K-9
K-9!
洛斯·泰勒 米奇·史密斯
Rose Tyler, Mickey Smith,
让我为你们介绍 K-9
allow me to introduce K-9.
准确的说是三代K-9
Well, K-9 Mark 3 to be precise.
为什么他看起来那么…
Why does he look so...
老土
disco?
喂
Oi!
听着 在5000年 这正是前沿风格呢
Listen, in the year 5,000 this was cutting edge.
他怎么了
What's happened to him?
有一天 他就…
one day, just...
无缘无故
Nothing.
你没试过修一修吗
Didn't you try and get him repaired?
这又不像拼迷你地铁那样简单
It's not like getting parts for a Mini Metro.
此外 他里面蕴含的技术
Besides, the technology inside him
可以改变人类科技
could rewrite human science.
我不能随便把他给别人看
I couldn't show him to anyone.
那个调皮的女士把你怎么了
Ooh, what's the nasty lady done to you, eh?
嘿  没有冒犯之意
ROSE: Look, no offence,
但你们两个能不能先别亲热了
but can you two just stop petting for a minute?
先别管那只铁皮狗了 我们还有事呢
Never mind the tin dog, we're busy.
你知道最让人惊讶的是什么吗
You see, what's impressive is that
自从遇到她已经一个小时了
it's been nearly an hour since we met her
我还一直没跟你说"我早告诉过你吧"
and I still haven't said "I told you so".
我不想听你说这个
I'm not listening to this.
然而我倒是准备了一支"我是对的"舞
Though I have prepared a little "I was right" dance
待会儿跳给你看看
that I can show you later.
两镑 美女
Two quid, love.
你老是不停的说"他很特别"
All this time you've been giving it "he's different",
但事实是 他和其他小伙子一样
but the truth is, he's just like any other bloke.
你不知道自己在说什么
You don't know what you're talking about.
不一定
Maybe not.
但如果我是你 我会少吃点薯条
But if I were you, I'd go easy on the chips.
到我这儿来
FINCH: Come to me.
过来
Come to me.
圣诞节时我觉得可能是你
I thought of you on Christmas Day,
圣诞节才过不久
this Christmas just gone.
天空中出现好大的太空船
Great big spaceship overhead,
我就想"太好了 他一定在上面"
I thought, "Oh, yeah! Bet he's up there."
没错 就在飞船顶上
Right on top of it, yeah.
和洛斯
And Rose?
她也在那里
She was there, too.
我做错了什么吗
Did I do something wrong?
因为你从不回来找我
'Cause you never came back for me.
你就这么丢下我
You just dumped me.
我说过了 我被叫回母星了
I told you, I was called back home
在那些日子里 人类是被禁止的
and in those days humans weren't allowed.
我一直在等你
I waited for you.
我想你
I missed you.
噢 你不需要我
Oh, you didn't need me.
你有自己的生活要过
You were getting on with your life.
你就是我的生活
You were my life.
你知道最困难的是什么吗
You know what the most difficult thing was?
适应回到这里之后的事
Coping with what happens next.
还有在这里不会发生的事
You know, with what doesn't happen next.
你带我到银河最遥远的地方
You took me to the furthest reaches of the galaxy,
让我见过超新星和银河战争
you showed me supernovas, intergalactic battles,
然后你就把我扔回地球
and then you just dropped me back on Earth.
还有什么比那更过分
How could anything compare to that?
你要我为你所看到的道歉吗
All those things you saw, you want me to apologise for that?
不 但我们体验过那种精彩的生活
No, but...we get a taste of that splendour and then we have to go back.
然后又必须回到从前
and then we have to go back.
看看你 你在做调查
But look at you, you're investigating.
你发现了那间学校 你还是像我们以前一样
You found that school. You're doing what we always did.
你可以回来
You could have come back.
我不能
I couldn't.
为什么
Why not?
不是在克罗伊顿
It wasn't Croydon.
你丢下我的地方不是克罗伊顿
Where you dropped me off, it wasn't Croydon.
在哪里
Where was it?
阿伯丁郡
Aberdeen.
对啊 但是离克罗伊顿也不远 不是吗
Right. That's next to Croydon, isn't it?
嘿 现在我们有事做了
Oh, hey! Now we're in business!
主人
Master?
他认出我来了
He recognises me!
确认
Affirmative.
洛斯 把油给我们
Rose, give us the oil.
最好不要碰到它
I wouldn't touch it, though.
那个食堂大妈都被烧焦了
That dinner lady got all scorched.
我可不是食堂大妈
I'm no dinner lady.
我也不经常这么说
And I don't often say that.
我们来吧
Here we go.
加油 伙计 我们开始
Come on, boy, here we go.
油 提…提…
Oil ex...
已提取
Oil extract.
分…分…分析中
analysing.
你听 天哪 他的声音
Listen to him, man! That's a voice.
注意点 那是我的狗狗
Careful. That's my dog.
分析结果
Confirmation of analysis.
该物质是克里腾油
Substance is Krillitane oil.
他们是克里腾人
They're Krillitanes.
情况不妙吗
Is that bad?
非常不妙
Very.
想象最坏的情况 再加上一箱子满满的不妙
Think how bad things could possibly be and add another suitcase full of bad.
什么是克里腾人
And what are Krillitanes?
他们是混合种族
They're a composite race.
就像你们的文化
just like your culture
是各种不同国家的文化的混合体
is a mixture of traditions from all sorts of countries,
侵入或者被侵入
people you've invaded or been invaded by,
你们有一点这个一点那个的血统
you've got bits of Viking, bits of France, bits of whatever.
克里腾族也一样
The Krillitanes are the same,
由各种被他们征服的种族混合而成
an amalgam of the races they've conquered.
但他们也能吸收新物种的生理特征
But they take physical aspects as well.
他们提取被征服者最有利的部分
They cherry-pick the best bits from the people they destroy.
那就是为什么我没认出他们
That's why I didn't recognise them.
我上次看见克里腾时
The last time I saw Krillitanes
他们和我们长得一样
they looked just like us,
只是脖子特别长
except they had really long necks.
他们在这里干嘛
What are they doing here?
是那些孩子
It's the children.
他们对孩子们动了手脚
They're doing something to the children.
那么这只铁皮狗是什么来历
So, what's the deal with the tin dog?
博士喜欢和同伴一起旅行
The Doctor likes travelling with an entourage.
有时可以是人类
Sometimes they're humans,
有时可以是外星人
sometimes they're aliens,
有时也可以是铁皮狗
and sometimes they're tin dogs.
你呢 你是怎么加入进来的
What about you? Where do you fit in the picture?
我  我是他们的得力助手
Me? I'm their man in Havana,
我是他们的技术支持 我是…
I'm their technical support, I'm...
噢 天哪
Oh, my God.
我就是铁皮狗
Oh, my God. I'm the tin dog.
听我命令...
On my command.
有多少人和你一起旅行过
ROSE: How many of us have there been travelling with you?
那很重要吗
Does it matter?
当然重要 如果我是排在最后一个的话
Yeah, it does, if I'm just the latest in a long line.
和什么做对比
As opposed to what?
我以为我们是…
I thought you and me were...
显然是我搞错了
I obviously got it wrong.
我也许去过50亿年的未来 但这个
I've been to the year 5 billion, right, but this...
这才叫做看到未来 你会丢下我们
Now, this is really seeing the future. You just leave us behind.
你会对我这样做吗
Is that what you're gonna do to me?
不 不会的
No. Not to you.
但是 莎拉·简
But Sarah Jane.
你和她曾经那么亲密 现在..
You were that close to her once,and now,
你甚至从不提起她
you never even mention her.
为什么
Why not?
我不会变老
I don't age.
我会重生
I regenerate.
但人类会衰落
But humans decay.
你们会衰弱并死亡
You wither and you die.
想像一下看到这些发生在你…
Imagine watching that happen to someone that you...
什么 博士
What, Doctor?
你的余生可以和我一起度过…
You can spend the rest of your life with me...
而我的余生却不能和你一起
but I can't spend the rest of mine with you.
我会活下去
I have to live on.
孤独一人
Alone.
这是时间领主的诅咒
That's the curse of the Time Lords.
时间领主
Time Lord.
那不是克里腾吗
Was that a Krillitane?
它碰都没碰你就飞走了
It didn't even touch you, it just flew off.
它为什么这么做
What did it do that for?
洛斯和莎拉 你们去数学教室
Rose and Sarah, you go to the maths room.
拆开那些电脑 我要看看里面的硬件
Crack open those computers. I need to see the hardware inside.
给 你们也许需要这个
Here, you might need this.
米奇 放风 我要你在外面
Mickey, surveillance. I want you outside.
站在外面就行
just stand outside?
给 拿着这个 你可以和K-9作伴
Here, take these. You can keep K-9 company.
别忘了把窗户开个缝
Don't forget to leave the window open a crack.
他是机器
He's metal.
这是为你好
I didn't mean for him.
你要做什么
What are you gonna do?
是时候和芬奇先生谈谈了
It's time I had a word with Mr Finch.
你是谁
Who are you?
我叫拉斯阿兄弟 你是
My name is Brother Lassar. And you?
博士
The Doctor.
克里腾族从什么时候有翅膀的
Since when did Krillitanes have wings?
现在离我们的原形已经更新了十代了
It's been our form for nearly 10 generations now.
我们的祖宗侵略了贝桑族
Our ancestors invaded Bessan.
那里的人有着可爱的翅膀
The people there had some rather lovely wings.
他们每天有一百万人成为寡妇 想像一下
They made a million widows in one day, just imagine.
而你现在是人型
And now your shape's human.
个人喜好 仅此而已
A personal favourite, that's all.
其他的呢
And the others?
我的兄弟们还是蝙蝠型
My brothers remain bat form.
你所看到的只是简单的形态幻象
What you see is a simple morphic illusion.
抓一下表面 真正的克里腾就能现形
Scratch the surface and the true Krillitane lies beneath.
而所谓时间领主呢
And what of the Time Lords?
我一直觉得你们是一个高傲的种族
I always thought of you as such a pompous race.
远古的枯燥无味的参议员
Ancient, dusty senators.
那么害怕改变
So frightened of change,
和混乱
and chaos.
当然了 他们几乎都灭绝了
And, of course, they're all but extinct.
只有你 最后一个
Only you. The last.
你所谓的计划是什么
This plan of yours, what is it?
你不知道
You don't know?
所以我才问
That's why I'm asking.
那让我看看你有多聪明
Well, show me how clever you are.
想出来吧
Work it out.
如果我不喜欢你的计划
If I don't like it,
我就会阻止
then it will stop.
有意思
Fascinating.
你们族人天生和平到几近慵懒
Your people were peaceful to the point of indolence.
而你似乎不太一样
You seem to be something new.
你是在和我们宣战吗 博士
Would you declare war on us, Doctor?
我现在很老了
I'm so old now.
我曾有如此多的仁慈
I used to have so much mercy.
只给你一次警告
You get one warning.
就这样
That was it.
但我们不是敌人
But we're not even enemies.
很快你就会和我们称兄道弟
Soon, you will embrace us.
下次我们再见面
The next time we meet,
你会成为我的一部分
you will join with me.
我向你保证
I promise you.
所谓放风
Surveillance!
要我说 只是换种说法让我
You ask me, it's just another way of saying,
远离危险物品在队伍后面乖乖待着
"Go sit at the back of the class with the safety scissors and glitter."
我竟然在和一只铁皮狗聊天
That'll be me talking to a metal dog, then.
不起作用
It's not working.
给我
Give it to me.
在以前总是一次就能管用的
Used to work first time in my day.
恩 现在的东西比从前简单多了
Well, things were a lot simpler back then.
洛斯 我能给你一点建议吗
Rose, can I give you a bit of advice?
我有预感你要这样做
I've got a feeling you're about to.
我知道你和博士的关系非常紧密
I know how intense a relationship with the Doctor can be
我不希望你认为我在破坏你们…
and I don't want you to feel I'm intruding...
我并没感受到威胁 如果你是那个意思的话
I don't feel threatened by you if that's what you mean.
行 那好
Right. Good.
因为我并没有兴趣吃回头草
Because I'm not interested in picking up where we left off.
没有
No?
一双伤心的大眼睛和机器狗狗
With the big sad eyes and the robot dog,
除此之外你昨晚还做了什么
what else were you doing last night?
我只是说重新适应地球生活有多艰难
I was just saying how hard it was adjusting to life back on Earth.
问题是 当你们两个见面后
The thing is, when you two met,
你可不止是想摆脱配给关系
you don't only just got rid of rationing.
难怪你会消化不了那些外太空事物
No wonder all that space stuff was a bit too much for you.
我对外太空事物并没什么问题
I had no problem with space stuff.
我见过的东西你都不会相信
I saw things you wouldn't believe.
说来听听
Try me.
木乃伊
Mummies.
我见过幽灵
I've met ghosts.
机器人 很多机器人
Robots. Lots of robots.
斯利辛人 在唐宁街
Slitheen, in Downing Street.
戴立克
Daleks.
戴立克国王
Mel: the Emperor.
反物质怪物
Antimatter monsters!
防毒面具僵尸
Gas mask zombies!
活生生的恐龙
Real living dinosaurs!
活生生的狼人
Real living werewolf!
尼斯湖水怪
The Loch Ness monster!
真的吗
Seriously?
听听我们俩
Listen to us.
就像我和我的朋友谢琳一样
It's like me and my mate Shareen,
我们唯一吵架就是为了男人
the only time we fell out was over a man.
而我们是在为博士而争吵
And we're arguing over the Doctor.
和你在一起时
With you,
他有没给你
did he do that thing where
以90英里时速解释某种原理
he'd explain something at like 90 miles per hour,
然后你一句"什么"
and you'd go, "What?"
然后他就会用一脸嫌弃的眼神看着你
and he'd look at you like you'd just dribbled on your shirt?
总是这样
All the time.
他还会不会经常抚摸塔迪斯的零件
Does he still stroke bits of the Tardis?
是的 是的 真的是这样
Yeah! Yeah, he does!
我就想说"你们两个需要独处一下吗"
I'm like, "Do you two want to be alone?"
怎么了
How's it going?
什么
What?
听着 我要找出这些电脑里面有什么程序
Listen, I need to find out what's programmed inside these.
什么
What?
停下
Stop it.
兄弟们 我们必须进入最后阶段
Brothers, we must initiate the final phase.
把孩子们叫过来并封锁学校
Get the children inside and seal the school.
我们的时代来临了 兄弟们
Our time has come, my brothers.
今天 我们将成为神
Today we shall become gods.
所有学生马上回教室
WOMAN". All pupils to class immediately.
所有的职工请到职工室集中
And would all members of staff please congregate in the staff room?
休息时间提前结束了 太好了不是吗
Break time's finished early! Isn't that fantastic?
不不 这间教室禁止入内
No, no, this classroom's out of bounds.
你们必须全都到南厅去
You've all got to go to the south hall.
去吧 南厅
Off you go, south hall!
这是什么情况 芬奇先生
What is it now, Mr Finch?
稍微调整一下时间表
Slight change in the timetable.
我们要提前吃午餐
We're having an early lunch.
打不开
I can't shift it.
音速起子不是能打开所有东西吗
I thought the sonic screwdriver could open anything.
除了是封死的
Anything except a deadlock seal.
这里面一定有什么东西
There's got to be something inside here.
他们教孩子什么东西了
What are they teaching those kids?
关闭学校
Close the school.
你要的程序
You wanted the programme.
那就是
There it is.
某种代码
Some sort of code.
不
No.
不 不可能
No, they can't be.
他们全被抓走了
They've taken them all.
什么
What?
他们把所有孩子都抓走了
They've taken all the children!
开关
Turn...
拜托 我需要帮助
Come on, I need some help.
系统重启 所有主设备运行中
System restarting. All primary drives functioning.
你能用了
You're working!
没时间解释了 我们要进入学校
Okay, no time to explain, we need to get inside the school.
你有没有…
Do you have, like,
我不知道 开锁装置之类的
I don't know, a lock-picking device?
我们在一辆车里
We are in a car.
或者钻孔装置
Maybe a drill attachment?
我们在一辆车里
We are in a car.
你一用也没有
Fat lot of good you are.
我们在一辆车里
We are in a car.
等等 我们在一辆车里
Wait a second. We're in a car.
退后
Get back!
造物范式
The Skasas Paradigm.
他们正在试图破解造物范式
They're trying to crack the Skasas Paradigm.
什么造物范式
The Skasas what?
上帝制造者 超统一理论
The god-maker. The universal theory.
破译了那方程式
Crack that equation
你就能控制构成宇宙结构的物质
and you've got control of the building blocks of the universe.
无论时间空间还是物质 都在你控制之中
Time and space and matter, yours to control.
什么 孩子们就像是一巨型电脑
What, and the kids are like a giant computer?
是的
Yes.
而他们学习能力被那些油提高了
And their learning power is being accelerated by the oil.
厨房里的那种油 就像
That oil from the kitchens, it works as
就像一个指导员一样
it works as a conducting agent,
使孩子变得更聪明
makes the kids cleverer.
那些油炸的薯条 我也一直在吃
But that oil's on the chips. I've been eating them.
59乘以35是多少
What‘s 59 times 35?
噢 天哪
Oh, my God!
但为什么要用孩子 不能用成人吗
But why use children? Can't they use adults?
不行 必须是孩子
No, it's got to be children.
上帝制造者需要想像力去破解
The god-maker needs imagination to crack it.
他们破解密码用的不只是孩子的大脑
They're not just using the children's brains to break the code,
还有他们的灵魂
they're using their souls.
课堂开始了
Let the lesson begin.
考虑一下 博士
Think of it, Doctor.
造物范式一旦破解 现实就会成为我们手中的粘土
With the paradigm solved, reality becomes clay in our hands.
我们能塑造宇宙并改进它
We can shape the universe and improve it.
噢 是的 所有生物都创造成芬奇先生的样子
Oh, yeah, the whole of creation with the face of Mr Finch.
叫我老古董吧 我还是喜欢事物原来的样子
Call me old-fashioned, I like things as they are.
你表现得像个激进分子
You act like such a radical
而你想做的就是保护旧秩序
and yet all you want to do is preserve the old order.
想像一下它能带来的改变
Think of the changes that could be made
如果这能力放在正确的人手中
if this power was used for good.
什么 像你这样的人
What, by someone like you?
不
No.
像你这样
Someone like you.
造物范式给我们力量
The paradigm gives us power,
但你能给我们智慧
but you could give us wisdom.
成为神
Become a god
加入我的阵营
at my side.
想象一下你能实现多少成就
Imagine what you could do.
想想你能挽救多少文明
Think of the civilisations you could save.
帕根那族 阿辛塔族
Perganon, Ascinta,
还有你的族人 博士
your own people, Doctor.
高高崛起
Standing tall.
时间领主
The Time Lords...
重生
reborn.
博士 别听他的
Doctor, don't listen to him.
而你们可以和他永远在一起
And you could be with him throughout eternity.
年轻 有活力
Young, fresh.
永不衰弱 永不变老 永不死亡
Never wither, never age, never die.
他们的生命是如此短暂
Their lives are so fleeting.
有太多的道别
So many goodbyes.
你这样多么孤独 博士
How lonely you must be, Doctor.
加入我们
join us.
我能挽救所有人
I could save everyone.
是的
Yes.
我能制止战争
I could stop the war.
不 宇宙必须向前走
No. The universe has to move forward.
痛苦和失去对我们的定义
Pain and loss, they define us
和幸福或者爱一样多
as much as happiness or love.
无论是一个世界还是一段关系
Whether it's a world or a relationship.
万物都有一个期限
Everything has its time.
万物都会结束
And everything ends.
出去
Out!
过来
Come on!
发生什么事了
What is going on?
他们是我的老师
Are they my teachers?
是的 抱歉
Yeah. I'm sorry.
我们需要博士活着
We need the Doctor alive.
至于其他的
As for the others,
你们尽情享用吧
you can feast.
K-9
SARAH: K-9!
建议你启动逃跑模式 女主人
Suggest you engage running mode, mistress.
来吧
Come on!
K-9 拖住他们
DOCTOR: K-9, hold them back!
确认 主人
Affirmative, master.
启动最高防御模式
Maximum defence mode!
来吧
Come on!
能量供应不足
Power supply failing.
别管这只乱咬人的狗了
Forget the shooty dog thing.
能量供应不足
Power supply failing.
是那种油
It's the oil.
克里腾人不能碰那些油
Krillitane life forms can't handle the oil!
没错 他们太频繁地改变生理结构
That's it! They've changed their physiology so often,
以至于自己的油都对自己有毒
even their own oil is toxic to them.
厨房里还有多少
How much was there in the kitchens?
好几桶
Barrels of it.
好的 我们要到厨房去 米奇
We need to get to the kitchens. Mickey...
现在怎样 帮忙拿外套吗
What now? Hold the coats?
让孩子们断线 然后带离学校
Get all the children unplugged and out of the school.
想想 蝙蝠 蝙蝠 蝙蝠
DOCTOR: Now, then, bats, bats, bats.
我们要怎么对付蝙蝠
How do we fight bats?
追上他们
Get after them.
主人
Master.
快来 狗狗 好狗狗
Come on, boy! Good boy.
好了 各位听着 我们必须离开这里
Okay, listen, everyone, we've got to get out of here!
它们都被封死了
They've been deadlock sealed.
一定是芬奇干的 我打不开
Finch must have done it. I can't open them.
这些桶抵挡不了我的激光定位攻击
The vats would not withstand a direct hit from my laser,
但我的电池快耗尽了
but my batteries are failing.
好吧 所有人从后门出去
Right, everyone out the back door.
K-9 跟着我
K-9, stay with me.
所有人 出去 马上
Everyone, get out. Now!
过来 动起来 走 走
Come on! Move! Let's go, let's go!
能量只够发射一次 主人
Capacity for only one shot, master.
为了最大程度的攻击效果
For maximum impact,
我必须处于大桶旁边
I must be stationed directly beside the vat.
但你会被困在这里
But you'll be trapped inside.
正确
That is correct.
我不能让你这样做
I can't let you do that.
没有别的选项了 主人
No alternative possible, master.
再见了 老朋友
Goodbye, old friend.
再见了 主人
Goodbye, master.
你是只好狗狗
You good dog.
收到
Affirmative.
K-9 在哪儿
Where's K-9?
我们必须走了
We need to run.
他在哪里 你做了什么
Where is he? What have you done?
一旦找到他
When we find him,
如果有必要就吃掉吧
eat him if you must,
但把他的大脑拿给我
but bring me his brain.
喜欢乱咬人的小狗
The little dog with the nasty bite.
现在没力气了 是吧
Not so powerful now, are you?
快点 伙计们 我们走 我们走
Come on guys, let's go, let's go! Come on!
痛苦
Burning!
你这坏狗
You bad dog.
收到
Affirmative.
太好了
Yes!
是不是和你有关系
Did you have something to do with it?
是的 有点
Yeah, I did.
噢 天哪
Oh, my God.
肯尼把学校炸了 是肯尼
Kenny blew up the school! It was Kenny!
肯尼 肯尼 肯尼
ALL:  Kenny! Kenny! Kenny!
对不起
I'm sorry.
没关系
It's all right.
他只是只笨蛋金属狗
He was just a daft metal dog.
没事 真的
Fine, really.
来喝杯茶
Cup of tea?
你重新装饰了
You've redecorated.
喜欢吗
Do you like it?
噢 我…
Oh, I...
喜欢 是的
do. Yeah.
我更喜欢它以前的样子
I preferred it as it was,
可以 这样也行
but it'll do.
我喜欢
I love it.
嘿 47乘369是多少
Hey, what's 47 times 369?
不知道
No idea.
现在没了 油的效力过了
It's gone now, the oil's faded.
但你还是很聪明的
But you're still clever.
足够配得上他了
More than a match for him.
我们俩都是
You and me both.
博士
ROSE: Doctor?
我们正要出发呢 不过
Um, we're about to head off, but
你可以跟我们一起来
you could come with us.
不
No.
我不能再这样了
I can't do this anymore.
而且 我还有更大的冒险要去呢
Besides, I've got a much bigger adventure ahead.
我是时候停止等待你
Time I stopped waiting for you
而去寻找属于自己的生活
and found a life of my own.
我能去吗
Can I come?
不是和你 我是说...和你
Not with you, I mean, with you.
因为我不是铁皮狗
'Cause I'm not the tin dog
而且我也想看看外面的世界
and I wanna see what's out there.
噢 答应吧 博士
Oh, go on, Doctor.
莎拉·简·史密斯 和 米奇·史密斯
Sarah Jane Smith and Mickey Smith,
总得有个史密斯在这里吧
you need a Smith on board.
那么好吧 我可以欣然接受
Okay, then. I could do with a laugh.
洛斯 可以吗
Rose, is that okay?
没事 很好
No, great.
为什么不呢
Why not?
我该走了
Well, I better go.
我该怎么做
What do I do?
要不要继续跟着他
Do I stay with him?
要
Yes.
有些事是值得你去为之心碎的
Some things are worth getting your heart broken for.
来找我吧 如果你哪天需要的话
Find me, if you need to one day.
来找我
Find me.
很疯狂
It's daft,
但是那次的事我还从没感谢过你
but I haven't ever thanked you for that time
而且 如我所说
and like I said,
我无论如何都不应该错过的
I wouldn't have missed it for the world.
有故事可以和孙子说了
Something to tell the grandkids.
我想现在只能是别人家的孙子了
Oh, I think it'll be someone else's grandkids now.
对 是啊 抱歉
Right, yes, sorry.
我还没机会问你
I didn't get a chance to ask...
你有没有遇到过什么人
There hasn't been anyone... You know.
是有这么一个人
Well, there was this one guy.
我和他一起旅行过一阵子
I travelled with him for a while,
不过他总是让人望尘莫及
but he was a tough act to follow.
再见 博士
Goodbye, Doctor.
噢 还不是告别的时刻
Oh, it's not goodbye.
说出来吧 拜托 这一次
You say it, please. This time.
说吧
Say it.
再见
Goodbye.
我的好莎拉·简
My Sarah Jane.
K-9
K-9!
女主人
Misstress.
但…你被炸毁了
But you were blown up.
主人重装了我
The master rebuilt me.
我的系统提升了很多
My systems are much improved
装了新的自适应超连接设备
with new omni-flexible hyperlink facilities.
他给你了换全新的外壳
He replaced you with a brand-new model.
确认
Affirmative.
是的
Yeah.
是他的风格
He does that.
过来 你 回家了
Come on, you. Home.
还有工作要做呢
We've got work to do.
确认
Affirmative.
我们被攻击了
We are under attack.
那些怪物
There are creatures.
我们阻止不了它们
We can't stop them.
我需要知道他们在找什么
I need to ﬁnd out what they're looking for.
只有一个办法能做到
There's only one way I can do that.
你在我的大脑里
You are inside my mind.
一艘51世纪的太空船
A spaceship from the 51 st century
偷窥一个18世纪的女人
stalking a woman from the 18th.
他们找到了正确的时间窗口
One of them must have found the right time window.
现在是时候全军出动了
Now it's time to send in the troops.
米奇
MiCkey!
壁炉架上的钟坏了 是时候了
The clock on the mantel is broken. It is time!
博士 博士
Doctor! Doctor!